CV

Mads Hvelplund Grækenlandsvej 129 2300 København S, Danmark

Mobile: 50550272

E-mail: mhvelplund@gmail.com
LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/limhvelplund

Stack Overflow: http://bit.ly/so_mhvelplund



I like the craft of software development, especially the process of understanding a complex business domain and reducing its problems to manageable chunks. My experience includes designing everything from individual features to complete platforms in domains from waste management to payment processing.

I have a strong background in Java, but I also have a good grasp of the .NET family of languages, and many modern JS frameworks.

On a personal level, I'm an extrovert and I get along well with people. I also enjoy learning from others and teaching them what I know.

Education

1995-2006: M.Sc. In Computer Science from DIKU, Copenhagen University

Certification

2018: AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Industry experience

Financial (online payment), 4 yrs. Government (health), 2 yrs. Insurance, 1 yr. Medical, 1 yr. Waste Management, 1 yr.



Work- and project experience

Novozymes (October 2019 - March 2020)

External Consultant

Role: DevOps

Description:

I helped rewrite the first iteration of Novozyme's AWS analytics platform. The work involved analyzing the existing work, and streamlining or reimplementing the platform in a more maintainable and extensible form.

Experience: Terraform, AWS, Ansible

JP/Politiken (March 2019 - September 2019)

External Consultant

Role: Architect, Developer

Description:

I designed and implemented a microservice platform based on Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS), and helped migrate the customer's existing code from Java OSGi to Spring Boot. The entire platform was provided with Platfor as Code using Terraform. A secondary responsibility was to help the customer's IT department find a way to work together with the new platform across teams. I also provided example applications for monitoring and management written in Spring Boot and React JS.

Experience: Terraform, Docker, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Spring Boot, Node.js, React JS

KeyCore / IBA (April 2018 - December 2018)

External Consultant

Role: Architect, Developer

Description:

Along with one other architect from KeyCore, I helped migrate the IBA's insurance sales platform from a single server hosted solution to a cloud native AWS application. My primary responsibility was migrating micro services and training the staff in the use of Git. I also wrote integrations that allowed developers to control and monitor deployment via Slack.

Experience: TypeScript, Docker, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Slack, Node.js, Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS), Amazon CloudFormation, AWS Lambda

Netcompany / KOMBIT (January 2018 - March 2018)

External Consultant

Role: Developer

Description:

I worked for KOMBIT on FLIS, a government platform for exchanging performance data between municipal leaders. My work dealt mostly with testing and optimizing in-house tools.

Experience: Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS), C#, Microsoft

SQL Server

.NET department manager, Theilgaard Mortensen (May 2015 - December 2017)

.NET department manager

Role: Manager

Description:

I managed the .NET department, consisting of 3 consultants. My team delivered both ad hoc development at hourly rates and an in house developed electronic patient journal system used by the Danish Government.

As manager, my main focus was on improving the quality of deliveries on our EPJ product. I introduced code reviews and mandatory unit testing, and worked with support to standardize integration testing prior to releases.

Experience: Code review, Continuous Integration, Integration Testing, Unit Testing

Electronic patient journal system (EPJ)

Role: Architect, Team lead

Description:

I served as team lead and architect for the team that maintained TM's EPJ systems for child dental care, post-natal healthcare, and the Copenhagen dentist school. The child dental care system alone had more than half of the Danish municipalities with every child in them as customers. The back-end was Java based and the front-end was a C# WinForms application.

Experience: C#, EPJ, GEPJ, Java, VB.NET, Web services, WinForms

Self-service modules for EPI system

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

Description:

I was the lead developer on the implementation of self-service modules for the EPJ system that integrated with NemLog-In.

Experience: Angular2, ASP.NET MVC, Bootstrap, C#, HTML5, Web services, OIOSAML.NET, SAML, SSO

Waste management portal

Role: Consultant, Systems Developer, Team Lead, Web Developer

Description:

I maintained waste management self-service portals for ISS and Novo Nordisk.

Experience: ASP.NET MVC, C#, HTML5, jQuery, MS Reporting Services, Web

services

Quality control

Role: Architect, DevOps

Description:

I developed and introduced Docker/DropWizard middleware to ensure that only tested code would make it into the main product branches, and to link auto generated change logs with the issue tracking system.

Experience: CruiseControl.NET, Java, Jenkins, Docker, Drop Wizard, Target

Process. Web services

Architectural review

Role: Architect, Systems Developer

Description:

I served as the main architect for most department projects, and I performed overhauls of the Java based back-end server's architecture, to replace homemade components with stock components from the Open Source community. The process helped reduce maintenance costs.

Experience: Bitronix JTA, Guava, Java, JAX-RS, Lombok, Web services

Log and server monitoring

Role: Architect, DevOps

Description:

I prototyped log- and server monitoring of our client solutions.

Experience: Docker, GrayLog, Nagios, NSClient, NXLog

Systems developer, Endomondo (January 2015 - April 2015)

Endomondo application back-end

Role: Systems Developer, Web Developer

Description:

I worked on the back-end used by the fitness app and the website during the transition from an Apache Wicket application to an OSGi/AngularJS solution deployed in AWS.

Experience: AngularJS, Apache Wicket, AWS, Java, OSGi, Web services

Unit testing

Role: Systems Developer

Description:

I rewrote the older parts of the backend to support unit testing.

Experience: JUnit, Mockito

Architect, DIBS (July 2010 - December 2014)

New Payment Gateway

Role: Architect, Team Lead, Systems Developer

Description:

I designed and prototyped a platform built around horizontally scalable servers deployed in Amazon's AWS cloud. The system used event sourcing and the CQRS pattern to share the load of processing payments, while simultaneously feeding a business back-end.

The final system was based on Axon CQRS and Redis, but during development both ActiveMQ and Riak where in play.

Experience: Apache ActiveMQ, Axon CQRS, AWS, MySQL, Redis, Riak, Spring, Web services

Server throttling **Role:** Architect

Description:

I designed, and helped implement, a configurable rate limiting proxy to during a hectic Christmas when the servers were buckling under the load. The system was conceived, developed and deployed over 48 hours, and was still in use 2 years later when I left.

Experience: Node.js, Redis, Web services

Systems developer, Eniro (March 2008 – June 2010)

Support tool

Role: Systems developer

Description:

I took responsibility for the in-house front-end used by the customer service department, streamlined the build process, and rewrote the application to use dynamic model binding.

Experience: Java, Java Webstart, Swing, Web services

Data integration

Role: Systems developer

Description:

I worked on the core data exchange collecting data from multiple sources and exporting them to the head office, providing data for both the websites and the print division.

Experience: Batch Processing, Java, J2EE 1.5, Web services

B2B master data portals

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I worked on several portal sites for B2B projects for the Swedish head office.

Experience: Java, jQuery, Freemarker, OAuth 1.0, Spring, Web services

Consultant, Theilgaard Mortensen (March 2006 - February 2008)

Lotus Notes integration

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I designed and developed an integration layer that allowed data from an

external data warehouse for Business Denmark.

Experience: J2EE 1.5, Web services

Bogportalen and Gyldendals Bogklubber

Role: Systems developer, Web developer

Description:

I developed e-commerce sites for a number of major Danish companies

including Gyldendal.

Experience: J2EE 1.4, WebSphere Commerce, Web services

Work experience matrices Area of expertise

Area of expertise	Last used	Years Experience
Architecture	2020	12
Back-end	2019	14
Consulting	2020	5
DevOps	2020	5
E-Commerce	2008	7
Frontend	2019	13
Government	2017	3
Open Source	2020	12
Payments (finance)	2014	5
Requirement Specification	2020	12
SOA	2019	14
System Design	2020	12
System Development	2019	14
System Integration	2019	9
Team Lead	2017	8
Waste Management	2017	1
Web Development	2019	6
Web Services	2019	14

Skill level description:

- 1. I've worked with this, but I'm rusty
- 2. I can maintain existing solutions
- 3. I can work confidently from scratch or existing code
- 4. I can teach others
- 5. The subject is a core competence

Technology	Last used	Years Experience	Skill level
.NET	2018	3	3
Ajax	2019	9	3
Amazon Web Services (AWS)	2020	10	4
Angular 2	2017	1	2
Ansible	2020	1	1
Apache ActiveMQ	2014	5	1
ASP.NET	2017	3	3
ASP.NET MVC	2017	3	3
Bootstrap	2019	9	3
C# (C-Sharp)	2018	3	3
Continuous Integration	2020	10	4
CruiseControl.NET	2017	3	3
Docker	2020	5	5
EPJ (Elektronic Patient Journal)	2018	3	4
FreeMarker	2014	7	1
HTML5	2019	9	4
IBM WebSphere Commerce	2008	2	1
Integration testing	2020	10	4
J2EE	2010	5	1
Java	2019	14	5
Java Swing	2010	3	3
JavaScript	2019	12	3
JAX-RS	2019	5	4
JAXB	2019	9	4
Jboss	2010	3	2
Jenkins/Hudson	2020	9	4
jQuery	2015	5	3

JSON	2020	10	5
LINQ	2018	3	3
Linux	2020	14	4
Microsoft IIS	2017	3	3
Microsoft SQL Server	2019	4	3
Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)	2018	1	1
MySQL	2015	8	3
Nagios	2019	4	3
Node.js	2020	5	3
React JS	2019	1	3
Redis (database)	2014	5	2
SAML	2020	4	3
Single sign-on (SSO)	2020	4	3
SOAP	2017	12	4
Spring	2019	8	4
Spring Boot	2019	2	4
SQL	2019	14	5
Swagger	2019	4	4
TeamCity	2019	1	3
Terraform	2020	2	4
Tomcat	2018	11	4
TypeScript	2018	1	3
Unit Test	2019	10	4
VB.NET	2017	1	1
Web Services	2019	12	5
WinForms	2017	3	2
WSDL	2017	12	4